Guide to the Edward Flanders Ricketts Papers, 1936-1979 (inclusive), 1936-1947 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
- Professional Work, Series 1
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Equipment suppliers, Subseries 1.3
    - Kimble Glass Co., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence
    - Lambooy Label and Wrapper Co., 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, ads, invoices
    - The Garraway Co., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, samples of photo reproductions
    - Linde Air Products Co., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence
    - Lunkenheimer Co. (and Republic Supply Co., distributor for Lunkenheimer), 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, ads
    - Marshall Newell Supply Co., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - EFR notes
    - Merchants Auction Co., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Invoice
    - Montgomery Ward and Co., 1936-1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, invoices
    - Noah's Arc Second Hand Store
    - Owen-Illinois Pacific Glass Co., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
    - Peninsula Typewriter Exchange (Fritz Wertmaan), 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
    - Proper and Gillespie, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, invoices
    - Republic Supply Co. of California, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Invoice
    - H.M. Royal, Inc., 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, invoices
    - Schwabacher-Frey Co., 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, ads, EFR notes
    - Sherman Clay and Co., 1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence
    - Specialty Glass Co., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, price quote
    - Standard Excelsior Co., 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, price quote
    - Tideway Press, 1937-1939 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Invoices, EFR notes
    - Undertaker's Supply Co., 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, invoices, EFR notes
    - Victor Equipment Co., 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, invoices
    - Vollrath Co., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence
    - Voltex Chemical Co., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence
    - Western Cooperage Co., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence
    - Louis Weule and Co., 1939-1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence
    - Dave William's Second Hand Store, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Invoice (also includes invoice from Noah's Ark Second Hand Store)
    - Zellerbach Paper Co. (San Jose), 1937-1942 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Invoices
    - Zellerbach Paper Co. (San Francisco), 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, invoice
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Shippers, Subseries 1.4
    - American President Lines, 1937-1945 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, bills, bills of lading
    - Minnick Transfer and Storage Co., 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Bills
    - Matson Navigation Co., 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence
    - Oregon-Nevada Fast Freight, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, bill
    - Southern Pacific Co., 1938-1946 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence
    - Pacific Motor Transport Co., 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Bills
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Property/Buildings, Subseries 1.5
    - Plans for new building, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Plans for new building; correspondence re: new building, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence re: waterfront property, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Blank lease agreement with Stanford University, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Del Vista Packing Co., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Designs and specs for furniture, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Building invoices, bills, receipts, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Fire, Subseries 1.6
    - Pre-fire inventory and papers related to lawsuit, 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Pre-fire inventory and papers related to lawsuit, 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Catalogues, Subseries 1.7
    - Pacific Biological Laboratories 1929-1930catalogue; collecting cards (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Library, Subseries 1.8
    - Donate Bindery, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Binding samples, correspondence, invoices, layouts, EFR notes
    - "Current data on binding Pacific Coast Libraries; Carcinology, Polychaetology, Malacology, Echinology, etc." (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Pacific Biological Laboratories -- Miscellaneous, Subseries 1.9
    - Pacific Biological Laboratories, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      note on folder "Compl. Code PL. Dec. 1933"
    - Museum specimens collected since the fire, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - New specs on crayfish and frogs, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Shark price list, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Advertising, price lists, 1937-1946 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Advertising, price lists, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Price lists, EFR notes, advertising, 1937-1944 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Slide price lists, cost accounting, ads, 1937-1943 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - EFR photo in envelope, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Notebooks, Series 2
  - "Polychaetes", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    (Notebook has "12 columns" printed on cover).
  - "Oceanography Notebook", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1. Chemistry, general
    - 2. Salinity
    - 3. Nutrients
    - 4. O2
    - 5. C02 pH
    - 6. Temperature
    - 7. Transparency
    - 8. Miscellaneous
    - 9. Waves, Currents, etc.
    - 10. Production, quantity
    - 11. Production, quality
    - 12. Bibliography
    - 13. Methods, tables
    - 14. Chlorinity
  - "Permanent (Expedition) notebool", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    (EFR list of contents inside front cover).
  - "Buff Survey R-C-R. Revised collecting reports (list of species taken): Cape Flattery to P. Conception Survey.", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Buff Survey Identity numbers. Specialists' reports: Cape Flattery to P. Conception Survey.", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Red Survey R-C-R. Revised collecting reports (list of species taken): West Coast Van[couver] I[slan]d-Queen Charlotte I[slan]ds.", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Red Survey R-C-R. Specialists' reports: West Coast Van[couver] I[slan]d-Queen Charlotte I[slan]ds.", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "EFR Toni - New Tidepool Book.", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Sardine notebook", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    (Has "RECORD" printed on cover and EFR list of contents inside front cover.)
  - "U.C. Notebook No. 1 re: Gulf book", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "U.C. Notebook # 3. Also WORD OF GOD MADE MAN", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    (Partial EFR list of contents inside front cover.)
  - "U.C. Notebook # IV", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Trip One. 1940 Trip to Mexico. Notebook One", 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    (EFR list of contents inside front cover.)
  - "Trip One. 1940 Trip to Mexico. Notebook Two. Bibliography", 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Second 1940 Mexico Trip. Notebook One. Includ. expenses", 1940 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Second 1940 Mexico Trip. Notebook Two", 1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "U.C. notebook No. 2 re: Gulf Book" (Box 13 (OS), Folder 1)
  - "HMS notebook. Gulf of California Data. Reading at HMS and UC" (Box 13 (OS), Folder 2)
  - "New Series Notebook No. 1." (Box 13 (OS), Folder 3)
    (EFR notes on cover: "Miscl and Personal Notebook". "E.F.R. started Febr. 12-13, 1941". "Including Abstracts for Btwn. Pac. Tides Nov. 1941 Rprtg.").)
    (EFR's list of contents inside front cover.)
  - "New Series Notebook No. 2." (Box 13 (OS), Folder 4)
    (EFR's list of contents, as well as typed list compiled by Hedgpeth, inside front cover.)
  - "New Series Notebook No. 3. Started late June 1944. Including Outside Coast Vancouver Island Expedition, June, July 1945" (Box 13 (OS), Folder 5)
  - "New Series Notebook No. Four. Started Sept. 1945, after first trip to West Coast of Vancouver Island." (Box 13 (OS), Folder 6)
- Personal records, Series 3
  - Taxes, Subseries 3.1
    - Social Security, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Notebook title "Social Security Date since Nov. 26-27, 1936".
    - Social Security, 1937-1942 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, tax returns, EFR notes
    - Monterey Co., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Receipt
    - City of Monterey, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Receipt
    - Sales tax, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Sales tax registration
    - Sales tax, 1937-1943 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence
    - Income tax, 1941-1947 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Withholding statements, EFR notes, tax returns, receipts, correspondence
  - Insurance, Subseries 3.2
    - Insurance: Ted Clark, Insurance broker, 1936-1947 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, invoices
    - Insurance, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence with insurance adjustor
    - Auto Insurance: P.A. McCreery, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, insurance statement
    - Auto Insurance: Decker and Smith Insurance Agency, 1937-1943 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, insurance statement, insurance cards
  - Auto Expense/Repair, Subseries 3.3
    - Auto Expense records, 1933-1936 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Autos: Ben's Auto Service, 1943-1946 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Repair records
    - Autos: Berthold Motor Co./Beattie Motors, Inc., 1937-1948 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, repair records, invoices
  - Miscellaneous, Subseries 3.4
    - Medical information, 1944-1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Medical information and bills
    - Personal data, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Birth certificate, selective service information, ID cards
    - Pacific Gas and Electric Co., 1937 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence
    - Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Co., 1937-1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, bills
    - Alcohol permit, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Permit and correspondence
    - Peninsula Credit Exchange, 1939-1941 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence
    - Bank of America, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
    - Hudson, Martin and Ferrante, Attorneys, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Statements of accounts, EFR notes re: army discharge
    - "Miscellaneous memoranda such as sizes of clothing, shoes, etc." (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Personal correspondence, Series 4
  - Capt. Peter Ackley, 1945; n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Dick and Janice Albee, 1937-1944 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - George J. Alexander
  - Matthew Allen (El Capitan Theatre), 1947 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - W.E. Allen (Box 9, Folder 10)
    See Box 12, Folder 12
  - Dr. Anderson
  - H.L. Andrews, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Burt Bayles, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hilary and Hope Belloc, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Almacen Benjaminson, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Heinz Berggruen, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Berkeley: University of California German & Spanish Departments, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Cyril Berkeley
  - S. Stillman Berry, 1941-48 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Boston: Museum of Comparative Zoology, Harvard University
  - Boston: Museum of Fine Arts, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Paul Budd, 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Paul Butler, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Mrs. John Cage III (Xenia), 1937-1947 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - California Packing Co. (J.E. McConkie), 1943 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Albert Campbell, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Joseph Campbell, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Chicago: Art Institute, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Chicago: Newberry Library, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - City of Paris (S.F. Store), 1937 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - David Clay (Box 9, Folder 18)
    See Harcourt, Brace, & Co.
  - W.A. Clemens (Box 9, Folder 18)
    See Nanaimo, B.C., Canada, Pacific Biological Station.
  - Cleveland: Cleveland Museum of Art, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - John and Alice Cohees, 1937-1938 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Mrs. Gretchen Schoeninger Corazzo, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - J.E. Cornwall, 1940-1942 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pascal & Dorothy Covici, 1939-1946 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Stanley M. Croonquist (Pacific Books), 1947 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - M.F. Cropley (Box 9, Folder 22)
    See Matson Navigation Co.
  - Russell H. Cummings, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Mr. David, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Elisabeth Deichmann (Museum of Comparative Zoology, Harvard University), 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - M.W. de Laubenfels, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Robert D. Dolman, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Rina Dorsey (pseudonym) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    See Virginia and Remo Scardiglie
  - Lucille Elliott, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Don Emblem [i.e. Emblen], 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Horace ("Sparky") Enea, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Betty Farmer, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Raoul C. Faure, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Peter Ferrante, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Henry George Fiedler (Scientific Books & Periodicals), 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Includes invoices
  - Byrant & Beth Fitch, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - James & Peggy Fitzgerald, 1937-1945 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Austin & Hazel Flanders, 1937-1940 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Howard & Emma Flanders, 1937-1939 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Buchhandlung Gustav Fock, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - C. McClean Fraser, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Norman & Jeannette Geschwind, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Andrew Gibb, 1937-1939 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Bob Gibbon, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Torsten Gislen, 1936-1947 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Steve A. Glassell, 1939-1946 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - J.E. Graff (Box 9, Folder 30)
    See Smithsonian Institute
  - Barbara & Elwood Graham, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - The Gramophone Shop, 1936-1947 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Horace Gunthrop & Son (Scientific Literature), 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Harcourt, Brace, & Co. (David Clay), 1942 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Joel W. Hedgpeth, 1939-1948 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Hewatt, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - The Hobby Shops (John J. Russell), 1937 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Hogarth Press Book Shop, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Mr. Hollister, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Albert D. & Flo Houpt, 1938-1944 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Mr. Hubbs, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Mr. Hunter, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - A.G. Huntsman (Box 9, Folder 33)
    See Toronto, Fisheries Research Board of Canada
  - L.H. Hyman (Box 9, Folder 33)
    See New York, American Museum of Natural History
  - Mr. Ingersoll (Ingersoll-Waterbury Co.), 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Mae & George Jenner, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Elizabeth Jensen, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Walter J. Johnson, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - A.P. Kashevaroff, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - G.J. Keady, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Herb & Rosa Kline (includes letter to Steinbeck), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Paul Knabe (Box 9, Folder 33)
    See C.V. Mosby Co.
  - Mr. Laughlin, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Paul Lechevalier (Box 9, Folder 33)
    See Paris, France, Federation Francaise
  - Letters of introduction, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Letters of introduction for EFR and Steinbeck re: 1940 trip to Mexico
  - Lisbon: U.S. Consulate, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - London: Annals & Magazine of Natural History, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - London: Linnean Society of London, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - London: Quarterly Journal of the Microscopical Society, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - London: Zoological Society, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Gwen Louise, 1939-1941 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Ritch & Tal Lovejoy, 1937-1946 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Bill & Karen Loynd, [1937] (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Matson Navigation Co. (M.F. Cropley), 1938 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - J.D. McEvoy, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - McIntosh & Otis, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - J.E. McConkie (Box 9, Folder 37)
    See California Packing Co.
  - Bob Meltzer, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Meriden Gravure Co., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Henry Miller, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - John L. Mohr, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Th. Mortensen, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - C.V. Mosby Co. (Paul Knabe), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Jean Murray, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Nanaimo, B.C., Canada: Pacific Biological Station (W.A. Clemens & Cyril Berkeley) [part of the Fisheries Research Board of Canada], 1938-1947 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Includes a series of letters and notes sent to Mr. Alan Baldridge of the Hopkins Marine Station by Hisao P. Arai of Rice University
    - Cover letter from H.P. Arai Jan. 22, 1969
    - Letter dated July 13, 1946
    - "List of species collected by Ricketts on west coast of island (mostly around Clayquot), Summer 1945
    - Letters dated 1947 Aug. 30; 1947 Sept. 9
    - "Ricketts summer 1946 collecting"
    - Letter dated Dec. 27, 1947
    - "Ricketts, June, July 1946"., 2 small pages of notes
  - Margaret & Gilbert Neiman, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New Haven: Bingham Oceanographic Foundation, Peabody Museum, Yale University, 1940-1942 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New York: American Geographic Society, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New York: American Museum of Natural History (Willard G. Van Name and L.H. Hyman), 1939-1948 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New York: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - New York: New York Zoological Society, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Ethel Oakley, 1938-1942 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - A.V. Okul, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Evelyn Ott, 1938-1943 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ottawa, Quebec, Canada: National Museum of Canada (Dr. Anderson), 1944 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pacific Books (Box 10, Folder 4)
    See Stanley M. Croonquist
  - Paris, France: Federation Francaise des Societies des Sciences Naturelles, Office Central de Faunistique (Paul Lechevalier), 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Paul, Lewis, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Peacock, Cpl. T., 1945 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Peninsula Herald (Monterey, CA), Letters to the Editor ("Lordy"), 1942-1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Science, 1939-1943 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Planck, Robert, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Price, Bob, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Price, Mrs. Elizabeth, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (London), 1943-1947 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Reinhard, Edward G., 1942-1944 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ricketts, Ed., Jr., 1937-1945 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ricketts, Nan ("Statements and History of the Nan-Ed situation to date with a few supporting letters"), 1940-1944 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ricketts, Nan, Nancy Jane, and Cornelia, 1940-1947 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - [EFR's father], n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ricketts, Thayer H. & Evelyn, 1937, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Rioja, Enrique, 1940-1943 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ruckeyser, Muriel, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Russell, John J. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    See The Hobby Shops
  - St. Louis: City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco: De Young Museum, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Salinas, CA: County Hospital, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Sangmaster, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Sardines, 1946-1948 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Sarro, Nick, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Scanlan, S. Gwyn, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Scardiglie, Virginia & Remo (and Rina Dorsey, pseudonym), 1939-1948 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - E.C. Schirmer Music Co., 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Schmidt, G., 1946-1948 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Schmitt, Waldo L. (Smithsonian), 1939-1947 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Schultz, L.P. (Smithsonian), 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Scientific Books and Periodicals (Box 10, Folder 17)
    See Henry George Fiedler
  - Seixas-Solomons, Theodore & Yvonne, 1941-1947 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Smith, Maxwell, 1944-1947 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Stafford, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Stanier, Roger, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - G.E. Stechert & Co., 1941-1944 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Steinbeck, John, 1942, 1946; n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Stephenson, T.A., 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Stevens, Pat & Jewell, 1941-1945 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Stockholm: K. Svenska Vetenskapsakademien, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Stone, George E., 1942 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Stratton, Malcolm, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - [Street, Webster (Toby)], 1942 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Tollerton, David, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Toronto: Fisheries Research Board of Canada (A.G. Huntsman), 1943 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Treadwell, A.L., 1943 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Treilhard, Julian G., 1937 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Tyler, John, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Ulrastem, Lars-Henrik, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - [Van Ghent], Cockie & Arie [Kruik], 1947 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Van Name, Willard G. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Victoria, B.C., Canada Provincial Fisheries Dept. (George J. Alexander), 1946 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Viking Press, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Marva, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Wall, Susan Vance, 1942-1944 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Walsh, Pat & Bob, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Ciriacy-Wantrup, S.V., 1939-1942 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Washington, D.C.: Biological Society of Washington, 1940-1943 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Washington, D.C.: Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Washington, D.C.: Fish and Wildlife Service, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Washington, D.C.: National Research Council, 1940-1944 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian Institution (J.E. Graff), 1940-1943 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Washington, D.C.: Superintendent of Documents, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - West, Marie, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - White, Bill, 1945-1947 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Wing Chong Co., 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott, 1936-1941 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Includes a history of shark liver oil
  - Woods, Loren, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Worcester, Mass.: Worcester Art Museum, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Manuscripts and notes, Series 5
  - Guggenheim Project (application for a Guggenheim Fellowship), 1946 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Manual of the Marine invertebrates of the Pacific Coast", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "Pacific Coast biology", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "Observation on the functions of parents", 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "Miscellaneous non-conceptual", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "Record desiderata", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Prints and reproductions: Desiderata", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Poetry (EFR's note on folder: "beautiful, beautiful poetry"), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "Vitalism", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "New scale" (music, harmonics), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Army diary and letters written from the Army, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - WWII indoctrination, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "Internationalism & Post-war reconstruction, Japanese-American talk", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "One man's approach to the Problems of international understanding" (incl. rejection letters), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Report and abstract on William L. Shirer's BERLIN DIARY, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Tobacco smoking and longevity", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Human relations", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Erotic fragment, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "Outline for the study of sex", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Jung, 'The Labyrinth'", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "Thesis and materials for a script on Mexico", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    (Note on folder: "additional data on 'the other side'")
  - Letters marketing essays (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Literary criticism, reviews, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - "Quietism vs. the deep thing", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    (note on folder: "also Bifurcation material vs. psycho.")
  - "The Universality of Duality - Relation between potentiality and reality (see also Hi-tension)", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Hi-tension (see also The Universality of Duality)", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - "Non-teleological thinking; Poetry essay", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 16)